<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emojis on Live Free or Dichotomize</title>
    <link>/categories/emojis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emojis on Live Free or Dichotomize</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/emojis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy World Emoji Day: an analysis of rOpenSci&#39;s Slack emojis</title>
      <link>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</guid>
      <description>HAPPY world emoji day! 🌍 🐔 📆
In honor of this momentous occasion, I have decided to analyze the emojis used on rOpenSci’s Slack.
library(&amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;) ⊕If you’d like to follow along, go fetch yourself a Slack token.
token &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;MY_SLACK_API_TOKEN&amp;quot; ## stick your token here We will first use Slack’s reactions.list method.
⊕Notice here I am pulling the items from the response and then from each item I am interested in the message reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>runconf17, an analysis of emoji use</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:47:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</guid>
      <description>I had such a delightful time at rOpenSci’s unconference last week. ⊕21 📦 were produced! Not only was it extremely productive, but in between the crazy productivity was some epic community building.
Stefanie kicked the conference off with ice breakers, where we explored topics ranging from #rcatladies &amp;amp; #rdogfellas ⊕for the record, I’m an #rchickenlady, IT’S HAPPENING to impostor syndrome. It was an excellent way to get conversations starting!
work Karthik and I worked on two packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence of drunk podcasts</title>
      <link>/2017/02/09/the-prevalence-of-drunk-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 12:56:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/09/the-prevalence-of-drunk-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>For today’s rendition of I am curious about everything, in Hilary Parker &amp;amp; Roger Peng’s Not So Standard Deviations Episode 32, Roger suggested the prevalence of drunk podcasting has dramatically increased - so I thought I’d dig into it 🚧👷.
I pulled the iTunes API for the term drunk in podcasts &amp;amp; plotted the results over time. I also finally found an excuse to use emoGG.
library(&amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;) library(&amp;#39;ggplot2&amp;#39;) req &amp;lt;- httr::GET(url = &amp;quot;https://itunes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CatterPlot thank you note</title>
      <link>/2017/01/25/catterplot-thank-you-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 12:18:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/25/catterplot-thank-you-note/</guid>
      <description>Lara Harmon has put in countless hours to build and uplift the ASA Student community. We are SO grateful. We know she loves cats, as evidenced by
⊕
On the off-chance you have not felt judged by a cat today, my cat can help you out. pic.twitter.com/sApgbyYztD — Lara Harmon (@Amstat_Lara) December 27, 2016   and
You&#39;ll notice that we have yet to be in a city where I can convince our design team cats would be 100% on-theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>