<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstats on Live Free or Dichotomize</title>
    <link>/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstats on Live Free or Dichotomize</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R release names</title>
      <link>/2017/09/28/r-release-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/28/r-release-names/</guid>
      <description>I always love discussions about R release names and their origin. I have been working on this list for a while – with the source release of “Short Summer” today, I thought it’d be a good time to post!
All of the release names are references to Peanuts strips/films. I think this is just so delightful! A few months ago, I attempted to get permission to embed the strips on our blog, but unfortunately it was denied (unless with had a limited audience with password protection 🤷‍♀️), so I’ve just linked to the comics – Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make an R Markdown website (with RStudio!)</title>
      <link>/2017/08/08/how-to-make-an-rmarkdown-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/08/how-to-make-an-rmarkdown-website/</guid>
      <description>We’ve updated our R Markdown website tutorial to depend on RStudio for simplicity. You can find our previous version if you would rather not depend on RStudio.
Setup Today, more than ever, a website is like a business card. As a graduate student or academic, by having a nice website you are not only providing a one-stop-shop for all of your necessary information, ⊕AND you are illustrating that you have the technical prowess to accomplish this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New and improved draw charts in shinysense</title>
      <link>/2017/07/27/new-and-improved-draw-charts-in-shinysense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/27/new-and-improved-draw-charts-in-shinysense/</guid>
      <description>Background I didn’t expect many people to use the you-draw-it charts (henceforth referred to as ‘drawrs’) I put into my shiny modules package shinysense but a decent number did, and with that usage came… bugs.
In an effort to fix the bugs I went back and tore the function down and re-wrote it entirely. This time I utilized the javascript and R development knowledge I gained from building it the first time ’round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter trees</title>
      <link>/2017/07/24/twitter-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/24/twitter-trees/</guid>
      <description>A little over a week ago, Hilary Parker tweeted out a poll about sending calendar invites that generated quite the repartee.
Do you like getting google calendar invites from your friends for lunches / coffees / etc.? — Hilary Parker (@hspter) July 19, 2017   It was quite popular 💅 – so much so that I couldn’t possible keep up with all of the replies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of &#34;We R-Ladies&#34;</title>
      <link>/2017/07/18/the-making-of-we-r-ladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/18/the-making-of-we-r-ladies/</guid>
      <description>Last March Maëlle wrote a blog post “Faces of #rstats Twitter”, a great tutorial on scraping twitter photos and compiling them in a collage. This inspired a similar adventure, but for #RLadies!
 One of our early brainstorm ideas, as Maëlle pointed out, looks a bit more like a kniting pattern. 
We brainstormed different ways we could make this collage unique, but ultimilately landed on creating a mosaic with the R-Ladies logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy World Emoji Day: an analysis of rOpenSci&#39;s Slack emojis</title>
      <link>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</guid>
      <description>HAPPY world emoji day! 🌍 🐔 📆
In honor of this momentous occasion, I have decided to analyze the emojis used on rOpenSci’s Slack.
library(&amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;) ⊕If you’d like to follow along, go fetch yourself a Slack token.
token &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;MY_SLACK_API_TOKEN&amp;quot; ## stick your token here We will first use Slack’s reactions.list method.
⊕Notice here I am pulling the items from the response and then from each item I am interested in the message reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the tuftesque blogdown theme</title>
      <link>/2017/07/13/introducing-the-tuftesque-blogdown-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/13/introducing-the-tuftesque-blogdown-theme/</guid>
      <description>This post will serve as a quick tutorial getting you from nothing to a customized blogdown blog using the theme built for this blog: tuftesque.
The tuftesque theme gives your blog a …tufte-esque… style that eschues some of the choices of the original and which I’ve added a few splashes of my personal style. The main title page is a single column and has an easily customizable banner where as the article view is the two panel view (for large screens) to allow for sidenotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useR!2017 digressions</title>
      <link>/2017/07/12/user-rundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/12/user-rundown/</guid>
      <description>We both recently attended useR!2017 in Brussels. It was a blast to say the least. We’re going to tag team to cover our favorite things &amp;amp; the lessons we learned while adventuring across the Atlantic.
Location Lucy: Brussels was incredible. The 🍺 was delectable and the people were delightful. ⊕This proved to be particularly useful when we temporarly misplaced our travel buddy Jacquelyn on our way from the ✈️ - we convinently followed the signs to wifi!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>runconf17, an analysis of emoji use</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:47:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</guid>
      <description>I had such a delightful time at rOpenSci’s unconference last week. ⊕21 📦 were produced! Not only was it extremely productive, but in between the crazy productivity was some epic community building.
Stefanie kicked the conference off with ice breakers, where we explored topics ranging from #rcatladies &amp;amp; #rdogfellas ⊕for the record, I’m an #rchickenlady, IT’S HAPPENING to impostor syndrome. It was an excellent way to get conversations starting!
work Karthik and I worked on two packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENAR in words</title>
      <link>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 14:56:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</guid>
      <description>I had an absolutely delightful time at ENAR this year. Lots of talk about the intersection between data science &amp;amp; statistics, diversity, and exceptional advancements in statistical methods.
&#34;By a small sample we may judge of the whole piece&#34; -- -- I loved it, but let’s see what others were saying! Check out this word cloud of the most commonly tweeted words.
This certainly sums up my experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga for modeling</title>
      <link>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:30:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</guid>
      <description>A New Year’s resolution for all of our models: get more flexible!
As an aside, I’m better at implementing yoga for my models than yoga for myself, most of the time I end up like this:
 Anyways, let’s make our models flexible! By flexible, we mean let’s be more intentional about fitting nonlinear parametric models.
What do you mean by nonlinear modeling By nonlinear modeling, we mean fitting parametric models with nonlinear terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>