<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstats on Live Free or Dichotomize</title>
    <link>/tags/rstats/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstats on Live Free or Dichotomize</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstats/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>rOpenSci Slack emojis</title>
      <link>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</guid>
      <description>HAPPY world emoji day! 🌏 🐔 📆
In honor of this momentous occasion, I have decided to analyze the emojis used on rOpenSci’s Slack.
library(&amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;) ⊕If you’d like to follow along, go fetch yourself a Slack token.
token &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;MY_SLACK_API_TOKEN&amp;quot; ## stick your token here We will first use Slack’s reactions.list method.
⊕Notice here I am pulling the items from the response and then from each item I am interested in the message reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>runconf17, an analysis of emoji use</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:47:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</guid>
      <description>I had such a delightful time at rOpenSci’s unconference last week. ⊕21 📦 were produced! Not only was it extremely productive, but in between the crazy productivity was some epic community building.
Stefanie kicked the conference off with ice breakers, where we explored topics ranging from #rcatladies &amp;amp; #rdogfellas ⊕for the record, I’m an #rchickenlady, IT’S HAPPENING to impostor syndrome. It was an excellent way to get conversations starting!
work Karthik and I worked on two packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENAR in words</title>
      <link>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 14:56:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</guid>
      <description>I had an absolutely delightful time at ENAR this year. Lots of talk about the intersection between data science &amp;amp; statistics, diversity, and exceptional advancements in statistical methods.
&#34;By a small sample we may judge of the whole piece&#34; -- -- I loved it, but let’s see what others were saying! Check out this word cloud of the most commonly tweeted words.
This certainly sums up my experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga for modeling</title>
      <link>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:30:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</guid>
      <description>A New Year’s resolution for all of our models: get more flexible!
As an aside, I’m better at implementing yoga for my models than yoga for myself, most of the time I end up like this:
 Anyways, let’s make our models flexible! By flexible, we mean let’s be more intentional about fitting nonlinear parametric models.
What do you mean by nonlinear modeling By nonlinear modeling, we mean fitting parametric models with nonlinear terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>