<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Live Free or Dichotomize</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Live Free or Dichotomize</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The traveling metallurgist</title>
      <link>/2017/09/29/the-traveling-metallurgist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/29/the-traveling-metallurgist/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: I made a thing that moves and has sliders and stuff. It’s down here.
Currently I am taking a class titled “Advanced Statistical Computing” taught here at Vanderbilt by Chris Fonnesbeck. The class is a fantastic whirlwind tour so far of some common optimization algorithms used in statistical computing. One of the algorithms I have found particularly fascinating is the “simulated annealing” algorithm. ⊕The whole algorithm is explained much better than I can do in the freely available Jupyter notebook for the lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commentary and follow up to p&lt;0.005 suggestion</title>
      <link>/2017/09/25/commentary-and-follow-up-to-p-0-005-suggestion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/25/commentary-and-follow-up-to-p-0-005-suggestion/</guid>
      <description>A recent paper, Redefine Statistical Significance by 72 (😱) co-authors, has caused quite a stir in the statistical community. Our student-run journal club at Vanderbilt will be discussing this contribution at our meeting led by Nathan James this week, so I’ve attempted to create a list of significant responses/commentary that have come out since this paper was posted on PsyArXiv.
This was compiled mostly via a quick Twitter search - please let me know what we are missing!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Slack Bot With Plumber</title>
      <link>/2017/09/03/a-simple-slack-bot-with-plumber/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/03/a-simple-slack-bot-with-plumber/</guid>
      <description>Intro To Plumber Plumber is an R package that allows you to create web apis in R. This is fantastic because it allows you to take your R code (models, database access, etc) and make them easy to access from anything capable of making http requests. This means a data scientist working at a tech company who has developed a fancy model using all of the tools at R’s disposal can make it available to their company’s app without needing to have a team of engineers port the model to whatever language the company uses for their back-end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Exponential Power Series</title>
      <link>/2017/08/14/the-exponential-power-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/14/the-exponential-power-series/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of the Poisson distribution, there’s something about its simplicity and elegance (I really like \(\lambda\)s) that makes it way easier to deal with than some monstrosity like the gamma or normal distribution.
Another thing I am a big fan of is the book I am currently reading: Surely You’re Joking, Mr Feynman. In one of the chapters, Dr. Feynman discusses his interest in the power series expansion of \(e^x\), and how efficient it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why you maybe shouldn&#39;t care about that p-value.</title>
      <link>/2017/08/14/why-you-maybe-shouldnt-care-about-that-p-value./</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/14/why-you-maybe-shouldnt-care-about-that-p-value./</guid>
      <description>Setup Recently, there seems to have been an uptick in citations of studies or statistics about this or that in the news and on the internet. As a statistician I think this is great. Anytime we can start to bring objectivity into our assessments of situations it’s fantastic. ⊕This is not to say all data/ stats are objective. Very frequently they can be very dangerously not so. However, I have also noticed some incorrect conclusions being drawn on the basis of these statistics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make an R Markdown website (with RStudio!)</title>
      <link>/2017/08/08/how-to-make-an-rmarkdown-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/08/how-to-make-an-rmarkdown-website/</guid>
      <description>We’ve updated our R Markdown website tutorial to depend on RStudio for simplicity. You can find our previous version if you would rather not depend on RStudio.
Setup Today, more than ever, a website is like a business card. As a graduate student or academic, by having a nice website you are not only providing a one-stop-shop for all of your necessary information, ⊕AND you are illustrating that you have the technical prowess to accomplish this!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New and improved draw charts in shinysense</title>
      <link>/2017/07/27/new-and-improved-draw-charts-in-shinysense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/27/new-and-improved-draw-charts-in-shinysense/</guid>
      <description>Background I didn’t expect many people to use the you-draw-it charts (henceforth referred to as ‘drawrs’) I put into my shiny modules package shinysense but a decent number did, and with that usage came… bugs.
In an effort to fix the bugs I went back and tore the function down and re-wrote it entirely. This time I utilized the javascript and R development knowledge I gained from building it the first time ’round.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter trees</title>
      <link>/2017/07/24/twitter-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/24/twitter-trees/</guid>
      <description>A little over a week ago, Hilary Parker tweeted out a poll about sending calendar invites that generated quite the repartee.
Do you like getting google calendar invites from your friends for lunches / coffees / etc.? — Hilary Parker (@hspter) July 19, 2017   It was quite popular 💅 – so much so that I couldn’t possible keep up with all of the replies!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The making of &#34;We R-Ladies&#34;</title>
      <link>/2017/07/18/the-making-of-we-r-ladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/18/the-making-of-we-r-ladies/</guid>
      <description>Last March Maëlle wrote a blog post “Faces of #rstats Twitter”, a great tutorial on scraping twitter photos and compiling them in a collage. This inspired a similar adventure, but for #RLadies!
 One of our early brainstorm ideas, as Maëlle pointed out, looks a bit more like a kniting pattern. 
We brainstormed different ways we could make this collage unique, but ultimilately landed on creating a mosaic with the R-Ladies logo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy World Emoji Day: an analysis of rOpenSci&#39;s Slack emojis</title>
      <link>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/17/ropensci-slack-emojis/</guid>
      <description>HAPPY world emoji day! 🌍 🐔 📆
In honor of this momentous occasion, I have decided to analyze the emojis used on rOpenSci’s Slack.
library(&amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;) ⊕If you’d like to follow along, go fetch yourself a Slack token.
token &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;MY_SLACK_API_TOKEN&amp;quot; ## stick your token here We will first use Slack’s reactions.list method.
⊕Notice here I am pulling the items from the response and then from each item I am interested in the message reactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the tuftesque blogdown theme</title>
      <link>/2017/07/13/introducing-the-tuftesque-blogdown-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/13/introducing-the-tuftesque-blogdown-theme/</guid>
      <description>This post will serve as a quick tutorial getting you from nothing to a customized blogdown blog using the theme built for this blog: tuftesque.
The tuftesque theme gives your blog a …tufte-esque… style that eschues some of the choices of the original and which I’ve added a few splashes of my personal style. The main title page is a single column and has an easily customizable banner where as the article view is the two panel view (for large screens) to allow for sidenotes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>useR!2017 digressions</title>
      <link>/2017/07/12/user-rundown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/12/user-rundown/</guid>
      <description>We both recently attended useR!2017 in Brussels. It was a blast to say the least. We’re going to tag team to cover our favorite things &amp;amp; the lessons we learned while adventuring across the Atlantic.
Location Lucy: Brussels was incredible. The 🍺 was delectable and the people were delightful. ⊕This proved to be particularly useful when we temporarly misplaced our travel buddy Jacquelyn on our way from the ✈️ - we convinently followed the signs to wifi!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>runconf17, an analysis of emoji use</title>
      <link>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2017 20:47:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/03/runconf17-an-analysis-of-emoji-use/</guid>
      <description>I had such a delightful time at rOpenSci’s unconference last week. ⊕21 📦 were produced! Not only was it extremely productive, but in between the crazy productivity was some epic community building.
Stefanie kicked the conference off with ice breakers, where we explored topics ranging from #rcatladies &amp;amp; #rdogfellas ⊕for the record, I’m an #rchickenlady, IT’S HAPPENING to impostor syndrome. It was an excellent way to get conversations starting!
work Karthik and I worked on two packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ENAR in words</title>
      <link>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2017 14:56:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/16/enar-in-words/</guid>
      <description>I had an absolutely delightful time at ENAR this year. Lots of talk about the intersection between data science &amp;amp; statistics, diversity, and exceptional advancements in statistical methods.
&#34;By a small sample we may judge of the whole piece&#34; -- -- I loved it, but let’s see what others were saying! Check out this word cloud of the most commonly tweeted words.
This certainly sums up my experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing shinyswipr: swipe your way to a great Shiny UI</title>
      <link>/2017/03/12/introducing-shinyswipr-swipe-your-way-to-a-great-shiny-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/12/introducing-shinyswipr-swipe-your-way-to-a-great-shiny-ui/</guid>
      <description>One day Lucy was sitting around on twitter when she spotted this tweet:
I built a “tinder for academic preprints” web app: https://t.co/fZYlgkn4WL for @biorxivpreprint preprints. — Jeff Leek (@jtleek) October 3, 2016   A tinder for preprints needs swiping though…
Hilarious 😂 If only it was compatible with swiping..the tactile enjoyment of making snap judgments by swiping left/right is unrivaled #papr https://t.co/isg5hmsh7n — Lucy (@LucyStats) October 3, 2016   Soon she remembered that I know a bit of javascript…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to GMD</title>
      <link>/2017/02/24/intro-to-gmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/24/intro-to-gmd/</guid>
      <description>Why The Problem You are working in a collaborative situation working on some form of analysis. You want to produce a nice looking document of your work at the end and have easy contribution from all sources.
 The Solutions Sit in one room and have one person write up all your work as you do it
Problems:
 source Use github with branches and pull requests.
Problems:
 Requires groupmates to all get second PhD in git.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The dire consequences of tests for linearity</title>
      <link>/2017/02/18/the-dire-consequences-of-tests-for-linearity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2017 09:03:06 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/18/the-dire-consequences-of-tests-for-linearity/</guid>
      <description>This is a tale of the dire type 1 error consequences that occur when you test for linearity.
 Edvard Munch’s The Scream (1893), coincidentally also the face Frank Harrell makes when he sees students testing for linearity. First, my favorite explanation of type 1 error 🐺:
 @jgschraiber @eagereyes Pro-tip that changed my life: in The Boy Who Cried Wolf, the villagers first make a Type 1, and then a Type 2 error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The prevalence of drunk podcasts</title>
      <link>/2017/02/09/the-prevalence-of-drunk-podcasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 12:56:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/02/09/the-prevalence-of-drunk-podcasts/</guid>
      <description>For today’s rendition of I am curious about everything, in Hilary Parker &amp;amp; Roger Peng’s Not So Standard Deviations Episode 32, Roger suggested the prevalence of drunk podcasting has dramatically increased - so I thought I’d dig into it 🚧👷.
I pulled the iTunes API for the term drunk in podcasts &amp;amp; plotted the results over time. I also finally found an excuse to use emoGG.
library(&amp;#39;dplyr&amp;#39;) library(&amp;#39;ggplot2&amp;#39;) req &amp;lt;- httr::GET(url = &amp;quot;https://itunes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yoga for modeling</title>
      <link>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2017 14:30:26 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/27/yoga-for-modeling/</guid>
      <description>A New Year’s resolution for all of our models: get more flexible!
As an aside, I’m better at implementing yoga for my models than yoga for myself, most of the time I end up like this:
 Anyways, let’s make our models flexible! By flexible, we mean let’s be more intentional about fitting nonlinear parametric models.
What do you mean by nonlinear modeling By nonlinear modeling, we mean fitting parametric models with nonlinear terms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CatterPlot thank you note</title>
      <link>/2017/01/25/catterplot-thank-you-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 12:18:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/25/catterplot-thank-you-note/</guid>
      <description>Lara Harmon has put in countless hours to build and uplift the ASA Student community. We are SO grateful. We know she loves cats, as evidenced by
⊕
On the off-chance you have not felt judged by a cat today, my cat can help you out. pic.twitter.com/sApgbyYztD — Lara Harmon (@Amstat_Lara) December 27, 2016   and
You&#39;ll notice that we have yet to be in a city where I can convince our design team cats would be 100% on-theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom JavaScript visualizations in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/2017/01/24/custom-javascript-visualizations-in-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/24/custom-javascript-visualizations-in-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>I happened to stumble upon the preview release page for RStudio recently and noticed something that made me exorbitantly happy.
 A preview release of RStudio v1.0.136 is now available for testing and feedback. This release includes… Support for JavaScript and CSS chunks in R Notebooks…
 “Support for JavaScript and CSS chunks in R Notebooks”! As someone who loves using javascript for plotting (and secretly for manipulating) data this is massively exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regression modeling strategies: a student&#39;s perspective</title>
      <link>/2017/01/17/regression-modeling-strategies-a-students-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2017 22:15:13 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/17/regression-modeling-strategies-a-students-perspective/</guid>
      <description>Frank Harrell teaches an amazing course “Regression Modeling Strategies” based on his book each spring at Vanderbilt.
This was one of my all time favorite courses. It has just the right amount of practical strategies, brilliant statistical insight, and zealous disdain for all things stepwise regression. In fact, Frank’s valiant fight against dichotomization inspired the name of this very blog.
This semester, Nick is enrolled in the course, and I will be TAing it, so we thought it would be a perfect time to do what all good 21st century students do, blog about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dplyr thank you note</title>
      <link>/2017/01/07/dplyr-thank-you-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 12:12:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/07/dplyr-thank-you-note/</guid>
      <description>It’s that post-holiday time of year to write some thank yous! I’m getting excited to attend rstudio::conf next week, so in that spirit, I have put together a little thank you using dplyr.
library(&amp;quot;dplyr&amp;quot;) dear &amp;lt;-function(input, you = &amp;quot;you&amp;quot;) { cat(input, &amp;quot;\nDear &amp;quot;, you, &amp;quot;,&amp;quot;, sep = &amp;quot;&amp;quot;) } thank_you &amp;lt;- function(input, for_the = &amp;quot;gift&amp;quot;) { cat(input, &amp;quot;\n Thank you for the&amp;quot;, for_the) } personal_touch &amp;lt;- function(input, from_the_heart = &amp;quot;I hope you have a lovely New Year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wait, what are P-values?</title>
      <link>/2016/12/24/wait-what-are-p-values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2016 15:50:12 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/24/wait-what-are-p-values/</guid>
      <description>Frequently, and especially recently, misunderstandings of common statistical terms/ concepts have caused confusion and even anger. I would like to (attempt) to clear up a big player in the world of commonly used (and commonly misunderstood) statistical concepts: the p-value.
  Stealing Lucy D’Agostino McGowan’s XKCD embedding strategy. TL DR A p-value is not a probability of the true parameter being something, but the percentage of times that the data you saw, or more extreme data, would occur given some “null” model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hill for the data scientist: an xkcd story</title>
      <link>/2016/12/15/hill-for-the-data-scientist-an-xkcd-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 15:41:30 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/12/15/hill-for-the-data-scientist-an-xkcd-story/</guid>
      <description>This was inspired by Hilary Parker &amp;amp; Roger Peng’s Not So Standard Deviations Episode 28, which can be found here. It was suggested that it would be useful to lay out Hill’s criterion for data scientists, I agree!

[causation: An event or outcome B is influenced by a change in A]

Sir Austin Bradford Hill, a statistician and epidemiologist, created a list of guidelines for evaluating whether there is evidence of a causal relationship.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>