<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Visualization on Live Free or Dichotomize</title>
    <link>/categories/visualization/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Visualization on Live Free or Dichotomize</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/visualization/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The traveling metallurgist</title>
      <link>/2017/09/29/the-traveling-metallurgist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/09/29/the-traveling-metallurgist/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: I made a thing that moves and has sliders and stuff. It’s down here.
Currently I am taking a class titled “Advanced Statistical Computing” taught here at Vanderbilt by Chris Fonnesbeck. The class is a fantastic whirlwind tour so far of some common optimization algorithms used in statistical computing. One of the algorithms I have found particularly fascinating is the “simulated annealing” algorithm. ⊕The whole algorithm is explained much better than I can do in the freely available Jupyter notebook for the lecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Exponential Power Series</title>
      <link>/2017/08/14/the-exponential-power-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/14/the-exponential-power-series/</guid>
      <description>I am a big fan of the Poisson distribution, there’s something about its simplicity and elegance (I really like \(\lambda\)s) that makes it way easier to deal with than some monstrosity like the gamma or normal distribution.
Another thing I am a big fan of is the book I am currently reading: Surely You’re Joking, Mr Feynman. In one of the chapters, Dr. Feynman discusses his interest in the power series expansion of \(e^x\), and how efficient it is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing shinyswipr: swipe your way to a great Shiny UI</title>
      <link>/2017/03/12/introducing-shinyswipr-swipe-your-way-to-a-great-shiny-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/03/12/introducing-shinyswipr-swipe-your-way-to-a-great-shiny-ui/</guid>
      <description>One day Lucy was sitting around on twitter when she spotted this tweet:
I built a “tinder for academic preprints” web app: https://t.co/fZYlgkn4WL for @biorxivpreprint preprints. — Jeff Leek (@jtleek) October 3, 2016   A tinder for preprints needs swiping though…
Hilarious 😂 If only it was compatible with swiping..the tactile enjoyment of making snap judgments by swiping left/right is unrivaled #papr https://t.co/isg5hmsh7n — Lucy (@LucyStats) October 3, 2016   Soon she remembered that I know a bit of javascript…</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom JavaScript visualizations in RMarkdown</title>
      <link>/2017/01/24/custom-javascript-visualizations-in-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 10:54:24 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/01/24/custom-javascript-visualizations-in-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>I happened to stumble upon the preview release page for RStudio recently and noticed something that made me exorbitantly happy.
 A preview release of RStudio v1.0.136 is now available for testing and feedback. This release includes… Support for JavaScript and CSS chunks in R Notebooks…
 “Support for JavaScript and CSS chunks in R Notebooks”! As someone who loves using javascript for plotting (and secretly for manipulating) data this is massively exciting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>